A true story of survival... declassified.
Rescue Dawn is a adventure, drama, war film directed by Werner Herzog.
A US Fighter pilot's epic struggle of survival after being shot
down on a mission over Laos during the Vietnam War.
Dieter Dengler, played by Christian Bale.
Duane, played by Steve Zahn.
Spook, played by Toby Huss.
Province Governor, played by François Chau.
Admiral, played by Marshall Bell.
Gene, played by Jeremy Davies.
Rescue Dawn is a 2006 epic war drama film written and directed by Werner Herzog.
It is based on the true story of Dieter Dengler, played by Christian Bale, a German-American pilot who was shot down and
captured by villagers sympathetic to the Pathet Lao during an American military campaign in the Vietnam War.
Steve Zahn, Jeremy Davies, and Toby Huss have
prominent supporting roles in the film.
In 1997, Herzog made a documentary film about Dengler
titled Little Dieter Needs to Fly.
Rescue Dawn, which focuses on Dengler's experiences as a prisoner
of war, began shooting in Thailand in August 2005.
It received critical acclaim, but was a box office failure.
The film explores themes of vietnam war, escape, war
crimes, prisoner of war, based on true story.
The tone is emotional.